<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cancer Genomics on Katie Huang</title>
    <link>https://github.com/kthuang20/Katie_Portfolio/tags/cancer-genomics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cancer Genomics on Katie Huang</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com/kthuang20/Katie_Portfolio/tags/cancer-genomics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Genetic Effects of Wnt Pathway on Pancreatic Adenocarcinoma</title>
      <link>https://github.com/kthuang20/Katie_Portfolio/post/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://github.com/kthuang20/Katie_Portfolio/post/project-3/</guid>
      <description>As the final project for my Cancer Genomics class, I analyzed the effects of genes in the Wnt pathway on TCGA data on Pancreatic Adenocarncinoma generated by the PanCancer Atlas. The Jupyter notebook walks through all the steps that were taken to clearn the data, analyze it, and obtain all values and visualizations. I also go through the scientific method, using the results I have gathered to ask a follow up question, develop a hypothesis, and test this hypothesis.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Discovering Driver Genes for Triple-Negative Breast Cancer</title>
      <link>https://github.com/kthuang20/Katie_Portfolio/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://github.com/kthuang20/Katie_Portfolio/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>This project showcases a comprehensive journey through the research process, from literature review to hypothesis development and model building. Beginning with a thorough examination of relevant papers, I formulated a hypothesis: whether FPKM levels of MYH11 could serve as a differentiator between triple-negative breast cancer and normal samples. Through meticulous data cleaning and exploratory analysis, I gained insights and visualized trends to validate my hypothesis. Utilizing linear regression modeling, I constructed a predictive model to discern average expression levels of MYH11 between triple-negative and normal samples, thereby contributing to the understanding of breast cancer biomarkers.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
