<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science Portfolio on Katie Huang</title>
    <link>https://github.com/kthuang20/Katie_Portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Science Portfolio on Katie Huang</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com/kthuang20/Katie_Portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Data Science Career Insights Dashboard</title>
      <link>https://github.com/kthuang20/Katie_Portfolio/post/project-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://github.com/kthuang20/Katie_Portfolio/post/project-6/</guid>
      <description>Curious about a career in the data science domain? This interactive dashboard offers a deep dive into the key factors influencing your decision. Explore real-time data on salaries, employment locations, remote work options, and more. Whether you’re considering data science or just exploring, this tool provides essential insights to help you understand if it’s the right fit for you.&#xA;Check it out here and make informed career choices with confidence!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predicting New Indications for Known Drugs Based on Similarity in Drug Signatures</title>
      <link>https://github.com/kthuang20/Katie_Portfolio/post/project-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://github.com/kthuang20/Katie_Portfolio/post/project-5/</guid>
      <description>Drug repurposing offers a quicker and potentially more cost-effective approach to finding new treatments by repositioning existing drugs with known safety profiles for alternative therapeutic indications. To accelerate the discovery of drug repurposing, the LINCS 1000 project has measured the in vitro effect of hundreds of drugs on gene expression across many cancer cell lines. Using this data, we propose a new approach to facilitating the discovery of new indications of known drugs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating Targeted Drug Discovery Against Antibiotic Resistance with CNNs</title>
      <link>https://github.com/kthuang20/Katie_Portfolio/post/project-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://github.com/kthuang20/Katie_Portfolio/post/project-4/</guid>
      <description>In this project, I tackled the pressing issue of antibiotic resistance by leveraging Convolutional Neural Networks (CNNs) to predict the efficacy of potential drug candidates in inhibiting β-lactamase, a key enzyme involved in antibiotic resistance. Using the ChEMBL dataset, I sourced canonical smiles of compounds known to interact with β-lactamase, which were then transformed into 2D images using RDKit for CNN input. By assigning labels based on pChEMBL values, compounds were categorized as either active (effective at inhibiting β-lactamase) or inactive.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Genetic Effects of Wnt Pathway on Pancreatic Adenocarcinoma</title>
      <link>https://github.com/kthuang20/Katie_Portfolio/post/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://github.com/kthuang20/Katie_Portfolio/post/project-3/</guid>
      <description>As the final project for my Cancer Genomics class, I analyzed the effects of genes in the Wnt pathway on TCGA data on Pancreatic Adenocarncinoma generated by the PanCancer Atlas. The Jupyter notebook walks through all the steps that were taken to clearn the data, analyze it, and obtain all values and visualizations. I also go through the scientific method, using the results I have gathered to ask a follow up question, develop a hypothesis, and test this hypothesis.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Compound Interest Calculator</title>
      <link>https://github.com/kthuang20/Katie_Portfolio/post/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://github.com/kthuang20/Katie_Portfolio/post/project-2/</guid>
      <description>Compound Interest Equation Used:&#xA;The inspiration for this user interactive calculator was based on https://www.nerdwallet.com/calculator/compound-interest-calculator.&#xA;I wanted to create this calculator to learn how compound interest works rather than simply plugging in the numbers into a website.&#xA;This web application allows the user to adjust the same parameters as on the website:&#xA;Initial deposit Contribution amount Contribution frequency Years of growth Estimated rate of return It also shows a scatter plot showing the total balance after each year with and without compound interest.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Discovering Driver Genes for Triple-Negative Breast Cancer</title>
      <link>https://github.com/kthuang20/Katie_Portfolio/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://github.com/kthuang20/Katie_Portfolio/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>This project showcases a comprehensive journey through the research process, from literature review to hypothesis development and model building. Beginning with a thorough examination of relevant papers, I formulated a hypothesis: whether FPKM levels of MYH11 could serve as a differentiator between triple-negative breast cancer and normal samples. Through meticulous data cleaning and exploratory analysis, I gained insights and visualized trends to validate my hypothesis. Utilizing linear regression modeling, I constructed a predictive model to discern average expression levels of MYH11 between triple-negative and normal samples, thereby contributing to the understanding of breast cancer biomarkers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://github.com/kthuang20/Katie_Portfolio/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://github.com/kthuang20/Katie_Portfolio/about/</guid>
      <description>I obtained my Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s of Science in Biomedical Engineering at UMass Lowell and am currently working towards my Master&amp;rsquo;s of Science in Biomedical Engineering and Biotechnology there. I am a self-motivated learner and with a growth mindset who is passionate and adept at computational problem solving and leveraging statistical methods in Python to build data-driven models aimed at helping develop more effective treatments for patients. I also love learning new things and mentoring others.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://github.com/kthuang20/Katie_Portfolio/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://github.com/kthuang20/Katie_Portfolio/contact/</guid>
      <description>Contact me on the following platforms:&#xA;Platform URL Email: katie.huang830@gmail.com LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/katiehuang20 GitHub: www.github.com/kthuang20 </description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
